Guide to the Al Block Broadcast Collection ARS.077
Archive of Recorded Sound
Al Block Broadcast Collection
1943-1958
ARS.077
Block, Al
2 boxes: 35 open reel tapes
Archive of Recorded Sound
Open reel tapes containing off-air recordings from the late 1940s through the mid-50s, particularly of Toscanini conducting the NBC Symphony Orchestra.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The Al Block Broadcast Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Al Block.
Scope and Contents
The Al Block Broadcast Collection consists of open reel tapes containing off-air recordings from the late 1940s through the mid-50s, particularly of Toscanini conducting the NBC Symphony Orchestra. There is little information enclosed about the performances, outside of principle performers and the date of broadcast; however, most of these programs have likely been documented elsewhere. The numbering for the programs was assigned by Block. Discrepancies between box and reel information imply that some boxes were mixed up over the years. The Toscanini recordings appear to have been originally made by a recording engineer at Westinghouse who had a direct line feed from the NBC studio console. His widow was contacted by a Toscanini collector, who then passed on copies (recorded at 7.5 ips half-track mono) to the donor.
Indexing Terms
Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957; NBC Symphony Orchestra.; Live sound recordings; Radio programs
- Toscanini, NBC Orchestra broadcasts
  - 1., 1944-01-03; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 2., 1944-02-17; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 3. Music of Old and New Russia, 1944-08-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 4. Guest: Artur Rubenstein, 1944-10-29; 1 7" open reel tape; Rubinstein, Artur, 1887-1982 (Audio 1)
  - 5. All Brahms, 1948-11-27; 1 7" open reel tape; Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 (Audio 1)
  - 6., 1949-02-19; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 7., 1949-03-19; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 8., 1949-12-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 9., 1951-02-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 10., 1951-11-17; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 11., 1953-01-31; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - 12. All Beethoven, 1953-02-06; 1 7" open reel tape; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 (Audio 1)
- 2. Other broadcasts
  - James Melton Entertains For International Harvester Employees And Family, 1950-06-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Box 2)
  - #15. Monteux, NY Philharmonic, Stern 11/12/1944; #13. Rodzinski, NY Philharmonic, Casadesus 10/29/1944; Stokowski, SF Symphony. NBC 12/5/1952; Walter, SF Symphony. Rehearsal, NBC 4/17/1953, 1944-1953; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Stokowski, Hollywood Bowl Symphony Orchestra. All Russian Program 6/19/1947; Brahms, Wagner Concert 7/18/1948, 1947-1948; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Rodzinski, NY Philharmonic, Milstein 12/31/1944; St. Louis Municipal Opera, CBS 6/26/1948; Toscanini, NBC Symphony. #45, 11/5/1944; #58 2/4/1945, 1944-1948; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #62. Percy Faith, Eleanor Steber 1943; #13. Music America Loves Best. Peerce, Romberg, Stewart 7/30/1944; #7. Great Moments in Music. Merry Widow - Peerce, Terryson, Weede. 8/2/1944; #5. Mitropoulos, NY Philharmonic, Brailowsky 11/3/1944; #31. Music America Loves Best. Maynor, Dorsey 1/7/1945, 1944-1945; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Stravinksy, Boston Symphony Dress Rehearsal 2/5/1949; Boston Symphony Dress Rehearsal 1/28/1949; Family Hour 9/30/1945; Walter, NY Philharmonic, Steber, Kullman 3/19/1944; Music Hall. Lawrence, Duchin, Foy, Ladd 5/15/1947; Oxycol Show 5/23/1950 [reel says "Reiner, NBC Symphony, Concert Hall, Teyte"], 1944-1950; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #164. Reiner, NBC Symphony, Goodman 11/6/1950; Concert Hall. Teyte, Brodsky; #22. Stokowksi, NBC Symphony 2/9/1944, 1944-1950; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Stokowski, Hollywood Bowl Orchestra, Grainger 7/15/1945; #287. America's Popular Music. Stafford, Weston; Walter, Standard Symphony Orchestra, Fleisher 6/12/1949, 1945-1949; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Music We Love. #43. Crooks 5/22/1944; #79. Sayao 2/5/1945; #106. Swarthout 8/13/1945; #61. Crooks 10/1/1944; #48. Crooks 12/14/1943; #75. Swarthout 1/8/1945, 1943-1945; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #44. Music We Love. Crooks 5/20/1944; #49. Great Moments in Music 5/30/1945; #56. Great Moments in Music 7/11/1945; #139. Concert Hall. Kriesler, Korenko 5/1/1945; #151. Concert Hall. Pinza, Casadesus 1945; #59. Concert Hall. Iturbi, Pinza 1945, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Koussevitsky, Boston Symphony. #47. 4/29/1944; #37. 1/9/1944; #49. 10/14/1944, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #18. Music America Loves Best. Thomas, Bampton, Kapell 10//8/1944; #28. Music America Loves Best. Warren, Korjus, Ellington 12/17/1944; #81. Music We Love. Steber 2/19/1945; #76. Music We Love. Stevens 1/14/1945; #78. Great Moments in Music. Peerce, Weede, Tennyson 2/2/9/1945; #71. Music We Love. Crooks 12/11/1944, 1944-1945; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #54. Music We Love. Pinza 8/4/1944; #150. Concert Hall. Heifetz, Traubel; #195. Concert Hall. Teyte, Brailowsky; #95. Concert Hall. Teyte, Rubinstein; #57. Great Moments in Music 7/18/1945; #41. Treasure Hour of Song. Peerce, Kirsten, Antonini 3/4/1946, 1944-1946; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Railroad Hour. Casey At The Bat 7/9/1951; Christmas sHow 12/25/1950; Vagabond King 3/5/1951; Blossom Time 10/31/1949, 1949-1951; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Music We Love. #64. Crooks 10/23/1944; #65. Crooks 10/30/1944; #76. Stevens 1/15/1945; #69. Crooks 11/27/1944; #51. Albanese 7/24/1944; #130. Gorin 1/2/1946, 1944-1946; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - United States Steel Hour, Conclusion. 7/23/1950; Encore NBC. Willson, Hayward 3/23/1953; Telephone Hour. Cummings 7/16/1951; #27. Longacre Opera Concert (Mutual). Nella, Scott; Standard Hour. Wallerstein, Schnabel 1/13/1946; Percy Grainger Christmas Seals Broadcast 1947, 1946-1953; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Railroad Hour. Katinka 5/28/1951; Rosalinda 3/12/1951; Countess Maritza 10/16/1950; The Years 1915-1920 7/13/1950; New Moon 1/29/1951; The Year 1925 6/26/1950, 1950-1951; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Railroad Hour. Madame Butterfly 4/23/1951; Annie Laurie 4/2/1951; Springtime in Paris 7/16/1951; The Year 1931 6/12/1950; The Year 1933 9/11/1950; The Prince of Pilsen 4/24/1950, 1950-1951; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Music We Love. #58 1/11/1944; #26. 9/2/1943; #102. 1/16/1945. Great Moments in Music. #13. 9/6/1944; #92. 3/27/1946. Music We Love. #84. 3/11/1945; #73. 12/25/1944 [reel says "Standard Hour, Abravanel, Szigetti"], 1943-1946; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Music We Love. #123. 12/10/1945; #37. 4/10/1944; #66. 11/6/1944; #45. 6/12/1944. Kostelanetz, Melton, Adler 1944; #94. Kostelanetz, Pons, 1944-1945; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #72. Music We Love. Crooks 12/18/1944; #48. Great Moments in Music 5/23/1945; #34. Music We Love. Crooks 3/17/1944; #65. Great Moments in Music. Peerce, Weede, Bauer 9/12/1945; #222. Music From America. Melchior 1/27/1947; #148. Music From America. Lawrence 8/27/1945, 1944-1945; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - #37. Black, NBC Symphony 9/10/1944; #239. Mitropoulos, NY Philharmonic, Casadesus 8/8/1958; #77. Music We Love. Swarthout 1/22/1945, 1944-1958; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Chicago Theater Of The Air. 12/11/1949; 12/18/1949; 10/30/1949, 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 2)